# Shane Fields

#### Software Developer

Auburndale, FI

863-450-5601 | shanefieldsdev@gmail.com
Personal Website | LinkedIn | GitHub

# **SUMMARY**

I am a proactive, bold, and growth-oriented developer with a strong drive and willingness to learn new things. I love creating simple and effective UI that optimizes user's experience. My personal mission is to further my specialization in frontend development, solve difficult problems, work with amazing people, and develop awesome technologies.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Technologies:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, SCSS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap **Related Professional Skills:** Algorithms & Data Structures, Git, Postman, and digital marketing.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Pomodoro Timer | Live site

- Web app that boosts productivity
- Ability to adjust focus and break duration.
- Tech: React and Bootstrap

#### Encrypter | Live site

- Web app that can encode and decode messages
- Uses Caesar Shift, Polybius Square, and Substitution Cipher
- Tech: JavaScript and Bootstrap

# Lord of the Rings HQ | Live site

- · Web app that gives information about Lord of the Rings
- Retrieves data via API
- Tech: React, The-One-API, and CSS

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer Jan 2022 - Present

#### **Shane Codes**

- Design creative websites with up to date technologies and practices.
- Work with clients to build modern and professional websites that best suits their needs.
- Support website stability and maximize SEO.

# Warehouse Manager - Sales

#### Florida Wire Fabricators | Winter Haven, Fl

Nov 2016 - Present

- Manage the manufacturing of wire products used by agricultural businesses around the country.
- Sales representative that contacts prospective clients and continue to build relationships with current clients.

# Package Handler

### UPS | Lakeland, FI

June 2020 - Present

- Assists in the unloading and loading of delivery trucks and the distribution of packages to other departments in the warehouse.
- Communicates with drivers and supervisors to optimize the organization of packages for each individual route.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Engineering Flex Program**

March 2021 - November 2021

#### **Thinkful**

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards.
- Focused on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node.js, and algorithms & data structures.
- Built comprehensive projects and collaborated with students and mentors to resolve issues and expand my skill set.